Theodosius Dobzhansky Papers ca.1917-1975 Mss.B.D65
American Philosophical Society
- Series I: Correspondence, ca.1920-1975; 7.5 linear feet
  Between 1969 and 1975, Dobzhansky also dealt with the conditions under which Russian geneticists in general, and Zhores Medvedev in particular, were working (see correspondence with M. M. Green, M. D. Grmek, A. Gustafsson, T. H. Jukes, D. G. Kenefick, I. M. Lerner and Medvedev (many in Russian); Muntzing, and van Gelder). Correspondence between Dobzhansky and his Russian colleagues was severely restricted by Soviet authorities for many years, nevertheless he was able to reestablish contact with several of them in the late 1960s, and approximately 175 letters in Russian are preserved in the collection. All date either from 1927-1935 or from 1968-1975, and among the significant correspondents are Y.A. Filipchenko, N.I. Dubinin, I.I. Schmalhausen, N.W. Timoféeff-Ressovsky, and Dobzhansky's former students, Julius Kerkis and M. Levit. Photocopies of Dobzhansky's letters received by Filpchenko, Vavilov, and Medvedev have been added to the collection courtesy of the State Public Library, Leningrad.
  - Abbitt, Raymond, 1970; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Abbou, Richard, 1973; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Abraham, J. C. B, 1970-1972; 4 items (Box 1)
  - Achievement Rewards for College Scientists, 1973; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Adams, Forrest H., 1971; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Adam, Hans, 1970; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Adams, Mark, 1970-1975; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Folder 1, 1975; 10 items (Box 1)
    - Folder 2, 1970-1974; 4 items (Box 1)
  - Agnew, J. D., 1973; 5 items (Box 1)
  - Ahrens, A. R., 1933; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Aldine Publishing Company, 1974; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Alexander, Richard D., 1974; 4 folders (Box 1)
    - Folder 1, 1974; 3 items (Box 1)
    - Folder 2, n.d.; 1 item (Box 1)
    - Folder 3, 1974; 1 item (Box 1)
    - Folder 4, 1974; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Alfert, Max, 1969; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Alger, Ian E., 1974; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Allard, Robert Wayne, 1971-1972; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Allen, Garland, 1969; 3 items (Box 1)
  - Almeida Machado, Paulo de, 1969-1971; 3 items (Box 1)
  - Alpatov, V. V. (Vladimir Vladimirovich), 1930; 2 folders (Box 1)
    Russian politics and science
    - Folder 1, 1930; 22 items (Box 1)
    - Folder 2, 1930; 2 items (Box 1)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1975; 2 items (Box 1)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1931-1962; 3 items (Box 1)
  - American Eugenics Society, 1970; 1 item (Box 1)
  - American Historical Review, 1973; 2 items (Box 1)
  - American Institute of Biological Sciences, 1973; 5 items (Box 1)
  - American Museum of Natural History - Distinguished Achievement in Science Award, n.d.; 1 item (Box 1)
  - American Philosophical Society, 1942-1975; 10 items (Box 1)
  - American Psychologist, 1972; 1 item (Box 1)
  - American Scientist, 1962-1974; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Folder 1, 1972-1974; 3 items (Box 1)
    - Folder 2, 1962; 1 item (Box 1)
  - American Teilhard de Chardin Association, 1970-1974; 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Folder 1, 1970; 19 items (Box 1)
    - Folder 2, 1970-1974; 15 items (Box 1)
  - Anderson, J. P., 1934; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Mel, 1971; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Wyatt, 1971-1975; 2 folders (Box 1)
    Biographical and personal data; Population genetics
    - Folder 1, 1973-1975; 11 items (Box 1)
    - Folder 2, 1971-1974; 4 items (Box 1)
  - Andros, Edward, 1973; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Angelina, Maria, 1974; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Anshen, Ruth Nanda, 1972-1975; 12 items (Box 1)
  - Ardrey, Robert, 1972; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Arieux, Marianne, 1974; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Arizona State University, 1969; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Arnold, Walter, 1973; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Ashton, Geoffrey C., 1970-1972; 5 items (Box 1)
  - Astaurov, B. (Boris L.), 1969-1974; 9 items (Box 1)
    Chetverikov, Sergei S.; Evolution; History of biology, especially genetics; Koltsov, N. K.; Russian politics and science
  - Ayala, Francisco J., 1970-1975; 13 items (Box 1)
    National Academy of Sciences; Population genetics; Publication
  - Ayres, Manuel, 1969-1970; 4 items (Box 1)
  - Babcock, E. B., 1934; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Babkov, Vasiili Vailevich, 1972-1975; 3 items (Box 1)
  - Bajema, Carl J., 1971-1973; 4 items (Box 1)
  - Baker, William K, 1961-1972; 5 items (Box 1)
  - Barker, J. S. F., 1973-1975; 5 items (Box 1)
  - Band, Henretta T., 1970-1975; 8 items (Box 1)
  - Bank, Lew, 1975; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Banlutal, Corazon O., 1974; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Bannister, Thomas T., 1972; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Banque Française du Commerce Exterieur, Paris, 1975; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Barbour, Ian, 1974; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Barchas, Jack D., 1972; 3 items (Box 1)
  - Barigozzi, C., 1972-1974; 6 items (Box 1)
  - Barnes, Carole Wolff, 1971; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Barnes, J. A., 1972; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Barnett, Thomas, 1973; 3 items (Box 1)
  - Barondess, Jeremiah A., 1973; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Barr, Thomas C., Jr., 1970; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Barrett, Paul H., 1974-1975; 4 items (Box 1)
  - Bashor, Philip S., 1971; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Basic Books, 1971-1975; 3 folders (Box 1)
    - Folder 1, 1975-1975; 17 items (Box 1)
    - Folder 2, 1972-1973; 6 items (Box 1)
    - Folder 3, 1971-1972; 14 items (Box 1)
  - Battaglia, Bruno, 1970; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Bauer, Hans, 1936; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Beadle, George W., 1961-1972; 11 items (Box 1)
  - Beardmore, John A., 1962; 17 items (Box 1)
  - Bearn, Alexander G., 1 item (Box 1)
  - Begon, Michael, 1974-1976; 4 items (Box 1)
  - Behavior Genetics Association, 1972-1973; 5 folders (Box 1)
    - Folder 1, 1972-1973; 19 items (Box 1)
    - Folder 2, 1972-1973; 8 items (Box 1)
    - Folder 3, 1972-1973; 9 items (Box 1)
    - Folder 4, 1973; 6 items (Box 1)
    - Folder 5, 1973; 6 items (Box 1)
  - Belgovsky, 1930; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Beliaev, D. C., 1975; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Bell, Michael A., 1973-1975; 11 items (Box 1)
  - Beltran, Enrique, 1958; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Bennett, Dorothea, 1974-1975; 4 items (Box 1)
  - Bennett, H. Stanley, 1961; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Bennett, William E., 1975; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Benoit, Jaques, 1961; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Benzer, Seymour, 1969; 6 items (Box 1)
  - Berg, L. S., 1935; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Berg, Paul, 1969-1970; 2 items (Box 1)
  - Berg, V., 1969; 1 item (Box 1)
  - Berlin, Sir Isaiah, 1970; 6 items (Box 1)
  - Bibliography, n.d.; 12 folders (Box 2)
    - Folder 1, n.d.; 4 items (Box 2)
    - Folder 2, n.d.; 2 items (Box 2)
    - Folder 3, n.d.; 2 items (Box 2)
    - Folder 4, n.d.; 1 item (Box 2)
    - Folder 5, n.d.; 1 item (Box 2)
    - Folder 6, n.d.; 7 items (Box 2)
    - Folder 7, n.d.; 1 item (Box 2)
    - Folder 8, n.d.; 4 items (Box 2)
    - Folder 9, n.d.; 5 items (Box 2)
    - Folder 10, n.d.; 1 item (Box 2)
    - Folder 11, n.d.; 5 items (Box 2)
    - Folder 12, n.d.; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Bijou, Sidney W., 1970; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Bingham, Ronald H., 1972; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Biography, 1973; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Birch L. Charles, 1961-1975; 37 items (Box 2)
    Ecology; Evolution; Population genetics
  - Birch, L. C., Review: The Biology of ultimate concern., n.d.; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Bird, Christopher, 1975; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Birdsell, Joseph B., 1970-1971; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Biswas, P. C., 1973; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Blackwell Scientific Publications, 1971; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Blair, W. Frank, 1972; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Blitzer, Leon, 1973; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Blyakher, Blacher, 1972; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Boardman, Harry, 1974-1975; 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Folder 1, 1975; 2 items (Box 2)
    - Folder 2, 1974-1975; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Bobbs-Merrill Company, Inc., 1972; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Bock, Carl, 1974; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Bock, R. Darrell, 1972; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Boerger, Mark, 1972; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Boesiger, Ernest, 1973-1975; 4 folders (Box 2)
    Conferences and symposia; Evolution; History of biology, especially genetics; Publication; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
    - Folder 1, 1973; 6 items (Box 2)
    - Folder 2, 1973-1974; 8 items (Box 2)
    - Folder 3, 1974; 15 items (Box 2)
    - Folder 4, 1975; 21 items (Box 2)
  - Bogart, James P., 1971; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Bogart Ralph, 1973; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Book reviews, 1938-1972; 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Folder 1, 1971-1972; 24 items (Box 2)
    - Folder 2, 1942-1962; 18 items (Box 2)
    - Folder 3, 1938-1972; 80 items (Box 2)
  - Bose, Normal Kumar, 1962; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Boslooper, Thomas, 1975; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Boucot, Arthur J., 1975; 3 items (Box 2)
  - Boughey, A., 1970; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Bowman, Barbara H., 1973; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Bowman, Robert I., 1961-1962; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Boyd, William C., 1970-1973; 3 items (Box 2)
  - Bradshaw, A. D., 1969-1971; 3 items (Box 2)
  - Braidwood, Robert J., 1961; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Brauer, Jerald C., 1970; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Braver, Gerald, 1971; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Brazil, 1973; 2 folders (Box 2)
    Political issues; Population genetics; Powell, Jeffrey R.; Teaching; Travel -- Brazil
    - Folder 1, 1973; 22 items (Box 2)
    - Folder 2, 1973; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Braziller, George, Inc., 1974; 6 items (Box 2)
  - Breitenbach, Robert P., 1973; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Breitenbuch, Bernd von, Jr., 1972; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Bridges, Calvin B., 1931; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Brieger, F. G., 1970; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Briggs, Robert W., 1970; 2 items (Box 2)
  - British Broadcasting Company, 1972-1975; 12 items (Box 2)
  - Broadhurst, Peter L., 1972; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Bronk, Detlev W., 1960-1970; 7 items (Box 2)
  - Brown, Sanborn C., 1974; 7 items (Box 2)
  - Bronowski, Jacob, 1970; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Brncic, Danko, 1962-1975; 13 items (Box 2)
  - Brumbach, Roger A., 1975; 2 items (Box 2)
  - Brune, Arno, 1974; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Bryson Vernon, 1962; 1 item (Box 2)
  - Burg Wartenstein Conference, ca. 1972; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Burgers, J. M., 1961; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Burgers, Mrs. L., 1974; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Burhoe, Ralph W., 1970-1974; 2 folders (Box 3)
    Conferences and symposia; Publication
    - Folder 1, 1970; 15 items (Box 3)
    - Folder 2, 1972-1974; 14 items (Box 3)
  - Burla, U., 1962; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Bush Donald F., 1972; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Bush, Vannevar, 1939-1940; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Butler, K. S., 1971; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Butler, Nicholas Murray, 1944; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Buzzati-Traverso, Adriano A., 1935-1962; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Callahan, Daniel, 1973-1975; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Camargo, Felisberto C., 1936; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Campbell, Bernard, 1968-1975; 9 items (Box 3)
  - Campbell, Donald T., 1972-1975; 2 folders (Box 3)
    - Folder 1, 1972-1975; 3 items (Box 3)
    - Folder 2, 1975; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Camper, N. Dwight, 1969; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Canadian Journal of Zoology, 1975; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Canfield, Cass, Jr., 1961; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Cappelletti, Vincenzo, 1975; 4 items (Box 3)
  - Carducci-Artenisio, Reine, 1970; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Carey, Jack C., 1973; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Carlson, Albert D., 1970-1971; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Carlson, Elof Axel, 1973; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Carlson, William D., 1971; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Carothers, J. Edward, 1971-1974; 5 items (Box 3)
  - Carron, Malcolm, 1974; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Carson, Hampton L., 1970-1975; 5 folders (Box 3)
    Biographical and personal data; Conferences and symposia; Ethical issues; National Academy of Sciences; Population genetics
    - Folder 1, 1970-1972; 17 items (Box 3)
    - Folder 2, 1973; 9 items (Box 3)
    - Folder 3, 1973; 5 items (Box 3)
    - Folder 4, 1974; 4 items (Box 3)
    - Folder 5, 1975; 9 items (Box 3)
  - Carter, Jack L., 1972; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Caspari, Ernst W., 1970-1975; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Castle, William E., 1933; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Castri, Francesco di, 1970-1971; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Catchside, D. G., 1971; 5 items (Box 3)
  - Cavalli-Sforza, L. L., 1970-1972; 5 items (Box 3)
  - Chase, Herman B., 1970-1971; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Chaudhuri, R., 1973; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Cheney, Brainerd, 1971; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Chipman, Robert K., 1972; 2 items (Box 3)
  - "Chromosomal", 1973; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Clarendon Press, 1971-1974; 7 items (Box 3)
  - Clarke, A. S., 1974; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Clarke, Bryan, 1970; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Clarkson College of Technology, 1965; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Clausen, Jens, 1969; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Cleffmann, G., 1975; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Cobb, John B. Jr., 1972-1974; 9 items (Box 3)
  - Cock, Alan G., 1975; 4 items (Box 3)
  - Cockerell, Theo D. A., 1932-1937; 4 items (Box 3)
  - Coe, Mrs. Michael D., 1959-1962; 8 items (Box 3)
  - Cohen, Barry Mendel, 1975; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Cohen, Bernice H., 1970; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Cohen, Chana Malogolowkov, 1970; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Cohen, Mortimer Theodore, 1971; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Cohn, Bradford, 1973; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Coleman, John R., 1973; 3 items (Box 3)
  - College of Wooster, 1945; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Collias, Nicholas E., 1973; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Colloque Mondial Biologie et Devenir de l'Homme, 1973-1974; 10 items (Box 3)
  - Colombera, Dario, 1973; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Colorado State University, 1973; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Columbia Today, 1975; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Columbia University, 1949-1962; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Columbia University. Dept. of Zoology, 1962; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Columbia University Press, 1961-1975; 19 items (Box 3)
  - Coluzzi, Mario, 1972; 5 items (Box 3)
  - Comas, Juan, 1971; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Commentary, 1974; 4 items (Box 3)
  - Commoner, Barry, 1970; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Coon Carleton S., 1962-1975; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Cooper. Christopher J., 1972; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Corbiere, H., 1969; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Cordeiro, Antonio R., 1967-1973; 7 items (Box 3)
    Population genetics
  - Cordón, F., 1962; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Corfman, Philip A., 1973; 4 items (Box 3)
  - Cornell University Press, 1974; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Corning, Peter A., 1973-1974; 4 items (Box 3)
  - Corson, David W., 1974-1975; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Cory, Lawrence, 1969-1971; 13 items (Box 3)
  - Coward-McCann, Inc, Publishers, 1970; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Crackpot letters, 1970-1974; 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Folder 1, 1973-1975; 8 items (Box 3)
    - Folder 2, 1971-1972; 6 items (Box 3)
    - Folder 3, 1970-1975; 15 items (Box 3)
  - Crandell, Merrell E., 1971; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Cravdns, Hamilton, 1972; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Crawford, M. H., 1970; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Creed, E. Robert, 1970-1974; 8 items (Box 3)
  - CRM Books, 1974; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Crow, James F., 1961-1972; 2 folders (Box 3)
    Behavioral genetics, IQ; Evolution; Muller, Hermann Joseph; National Academy of Sciences; Shockley, William; Wallace, Bruce; Wright, Sewall
    - Folder 1, 1970-1972; 8 items (Box 3)
    - Folder 2, 1961-1962; 7 items (Box 3)
  - Crowell, Thomas Y., Company, 1974; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Cruise, John, 1970; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Crumpacker, David Wilson, 1969-1975; 2 folders (Box 3)
    Population genetics; Recommendations -- Richmond, Rollin C.; Research support; Travel -- Invitations, arrangements
    - Folder 1, 1975; 13 items (Box 3)
    - Folder 2, 1968-1970; 12 items (Box 3)
  - Crutchfield, Richard S., 1971; 1 item (Box 3)
  - Cuenca, Carlos Luis de, 1975; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Cullen, Joseph W., 1971; 3 items (Box 3)
  - Cunha, Antonio B. da, 1962-1975; 18 items (Box 3)
    Biographical and personal data; Population genetics; Publication; Travel -- Brazil
  - Current Anthropology Journal, 1973; 2 items (Box 3)
  - Daeley, John, 1970; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Dane, Albert E., 1974; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Dansereau, Pierre, 1968; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Darlington, Cyril Dean, 1933-1974; 6 items (Box 4)
    Cytogenetics; Political issues; Reviews; Travel -- India; Travel -- Japan; World War II -- Impact on science
  - Darwin, Charles Robert, 1958-1959; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Dausset, Jean, 1971; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Davenport, Demorest, 1970-1975; 5 items (Box 4)
  - Davenport, John W., 1970; 4 items (Box 4)
  - David, Edward E., Jr, 1972; 2 items (Box 4)
  - David, Jean, 1974-1975; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Davidheiser, Bolton, 1975; 12 items (Box 4)
  - Davis, Bernard D., 1970-1974; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Davis, Fred, 1973; 8 items (Box 4)
  - Davis, Kingsley, 1970; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Davitashvili, 1966-1969; 6 items (Box 4)
  - Dawood, Mahoud, 1971; 3 items (Box 4)
  - Dawson, Peter S., 1970-1973; 2 items (Box 4)
  - DeFries, John C., 1970-1972; 3 items (Box 4)
  - DeGaray, Alfonso Leon, 1970-1975; 4 folders (Box 4)
    Evolution; Invitations; Population genetics
    - Folder 1, 1970-1971; 2 items (Box 4)
    - Folder 2, 1971-1974; 8 items (Box 4)
    - Folder 3, 1975; 16 items (Box 4)
    - Folder 4, 1975; 5 items (Box 4)
  - Delden, W. V., 1970; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Delsol, Michel, 1974; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Demerec, Milislav, 1936-1939; 7 items (Box 4)
    Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Columbia University; Drosophila genetics; Research support
  - Dempster, Everett, 1970; 3 items (Box 4)
  - DaMurtas, A., 1972; 3 items (Box 4)
  - Dessauer, Herbert, 1974-1975; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Dethier, Vincent G, 1970; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Deutsche Akademie der Naturforscher Leopoldina, 1970; 2 items (Box 4)
  - DeVore, Irven, 1970-1971; 8 items (Box 4)
  - Dewey, Maynard M., 1970-1973; 2 items (Box 4)
  - DeWit, J. J. Duyvené, 1964; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Deinstman, Steven R, 1970; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Dillé, John E., 1973; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Dimond, Stuart J., ca.1976; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Dingle, Hugh, 1971; 3 items (Box 4)
  - Diplomas, 1945-1968; 8 items (Box 4)
  - Dische, Zacharias, 1973; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Ditfurth, Hoimar von, 1973; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Are Men Born Unequal After All?, 1970; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Autogiographical Note, n.d.; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Belem do Para, 1952; 3 items (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Catholicity and Mission to the World, 2 items (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Cedrus Libani, 1956; 3 items (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Columbia's Pacific Outlet, 1958; 5 items (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Concerning holes in academic gowns, 1953; 3 items (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Condor's feathers, 1956; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Crisis of Soviet Biology, 1954; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Crumbs from the table of Mr. Ford, 1952; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Darkness in the Forest, 1958; 3 items (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Equator in the back yard, 1952(?); 4 items (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Faces of Shiva, 1960; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Finis Terrae, 1956; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Guests Behaving Inconveniently Shall Be Asked to Leave the Hotel Immediately, 1955; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., In the Bulge, 1955; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Indonesia, 1960; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Land of the Flatheads, 1956; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Land of Friendly Cannibals, 1960; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Mendelismus, Darwinismus und Evolutionismus, 1967; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Personal, 1973-1974; 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Folder 1, 1973-1974; 18 items (Box 4)
    - Folder 2, 1974; 11 items (Box 4)
    - Folder 3, 1974; 3 items (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Peru and the Andes, 1955; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Photographs, etc., 1975; 18 items (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Population Genetics of Mexican Drosophila, 1975; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Revolution Brazilian style, 1955; 3 items (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Strangling Fig Trees, 2 items (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., The Sweet River, 1952; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Three Crowded Days in the Holy Land, 1956; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Validity of the Gene Theory, n.d.; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Venture that nearly failed, 1952; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Dobzhansky, T., Where tourists never come, 1952; 6 items (Box 4)
  - Dodson, Edward O., 1971-1973; 5 items (Box 4)
  - Dolhinow, Phyllis, 1971; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Dornfeld, Ernest, 1970; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Dowden, Hutchinson and Ross, Inc., 1973; 6 items (Box 4)
  - Doxiadis, 1971; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Doyden, John P, 1975; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Dragan, M., 1974; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Dronamraju, K R., 1970-1971; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Druger, Marvin, 1970-1973; 10 items (Box 4)
  - Dubinin, Nikolai Petrovich, 1936, 1967-1969; 3 folders (Box 4)
    Biographical and personal data; Genetics
    - Folder 1, 1967-1969; 7 items (Box 4)
    - Folder 2, 1936; 1 item (Box 4)
    - Folder 3, 1936; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Duchrow, Ulrich, 1970; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Duckett, Jeanie, 1972; 1 item (Box 4)
  - Dunn, G. M., 1974; 2 items (Box 4)
  - Dunn, Leslie Clarence, 1936-1974; 3 folders (Box 4)
    Biographical and personal data; Columbia University; Drosophila genetics
    - Folder 1, 1974; 1 item
    - Folder 2, 1961; 6 items
    - Folder 3, 1936-1940; 11 items
  - Dunn, Louise, 1974-1975; 11 items (Box 4)
  - Dutton, E. P., and Company, Inc., 1970-1972; 7 items (Box 4)
  - Dyson Hudson, Rada, 1970-1974; 7 items (Box 4)
  - Easton, Michael, 1973; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Ebling, F. J., 1974; 3 items (Box 5)
  - Eccles, John C., 1970-1973; 6 items (Box 5)
  - Eckhardt, Robert B, 1972; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Eckland, Bruce K., 1970-1974; 12 items (Box 5)
  - Eckstrand, Irene Anne, 1974-1975; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Ecology Center Communications Council, 1971; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Editora Pedagóga e Universitária Ltda, 1975; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Edizioni Scientifiche e Tecniche, Mondadori, 1970-1972; 6 items (Box 5)
  - Edlin, Gordon, n.d.; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Edwards, A. W. F., 1972; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Edwards, Marvin L, 1970; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Egyptian Journal of Genetics and Cytology, 1971; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Ehrlich, Paul R., 1970-1971; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Ehrman, Lee Rothschild, 1971-1976; 3 folders (Box 5)
    Ayala, Francisco J.; Biographical and personal data; Laboratory techniques, equipment; Political issues -- Chile; Population genetics; Publication
    - Folder 1, 1971-1972; 7 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 2, 1972-1973; 11 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 3, 1974-1976; 6 items (Box 5)
  - Eibl-Eibesfeldt, I., 1974; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Eiseley, Loren, 1972-1973; 3 items (Box 5)
  - Eisner, Thomas, 1972; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Elens, A. I., 1970; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Elliot, Pamela, 1971; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Elovson, Jo, 1971; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Elston, Robert C, 1972; 1 item (Box 5)
  - EMBO Workshop on Molecular Evolution, 1974; 12 items (Box 5)
  - Emboden, William A., 1975; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Emerson, Alfred E., 1961-1962; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Encyclopedia Americana, 1970-1971; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Encyclopaedia Britannica, 1971-1974; 7 items (Box 5)
  - Encyclopaedia of the Future, 1973; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Encyclopedia Universalis, 1972; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Endler John A., 1973; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Epling, Carl, ca. 1963; 3 items (Box 5)
    Biographical and personal data; Ethical issues; Travel -- Ecuador
  - Erasmus, Charles J., 1974; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Erlenmeyer-Kimling, L., 1972-1975; 3 items (Box 5)
  - Estrada, Rodolfo Felix
    See Félix Estrada, Rodolfo
  - Evans, E. Burke, 1972; 4 items (Box 5)
  - Evolution (periodical), 1970-1975; 12 items (Box 5)
  - Evolution (book), 1973-1975; 2 items (Box 5)
  - Evolution Protest Movement, 1961; 1 item (Box 5)
  - Evolutionary Biology, 1967-1975; 19 folders (Box 5)
    Editorial matters; Evolution; Publication -- Evolutionary Biology
    - Folder 1, 1967-1970; 13 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 2, 1970; 15 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 3, 1971 - 1972; 19 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 4, 1972; 13 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 5, 1972; 17 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 6, 1972; 2 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 7, 1972; 1 item (Box 5)
    - Folder 8, 1972; 1 item (Box 5)
    - Folder 9, 1972; 14 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 10, 1973; 14 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 11, 1973; 20 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 12, 1973; 14 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 13, 1973; 14 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 14, 1974; 14 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 15, 1974; 17 items (Box 5)
    - Folder 16, 1974; 27 items (Box 5)